JADE LOPEZ

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

Colorado Springs, CO

909-379-4021

🔀 jadeli1720@gmail.com

🌎 <u>www.jadeelopez.com</u>

linkedin.com/jadeli1720

🌎 github.com/jadeli1720

SUMMARY

Graphic Designer/Full-stack software engineer with 14 years in the customer service industry. Focused on creating useful products that provide meaningful and relevant experiences to users. Experienced in building products in a team setting and motivated to learn new technologies to grow as a developer and individual.

SKILLS

FRONT END: HTML, CSS, LESS, SASS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Angular, React, Redux, Responsive Design

BACK END: REST, Node, Express, Sqlite3, Python

Tools: GIT, Heroku, Ziet, Jira, Bitbucket, Confluence, VS Code, Adobe Creative Suite, Coral Painter

EDUCATION

2020 Lambda School, Remote Full Stack Web Development

2019 Foothill College, Remote AA in Graphic & Interactive Design

2010 San Francisco State University
Music - Opera

INTERESTS

SINGING UPERA

STAR TREK

OBSESSED WITH ASSASSIN'S CREED

PROJECTS

CyberPunk Mud | Jan 2020 | cypberpunkmud.now.sh/

React, Redux, React-Vis, Sass, Python, Django, PostgreSQL

Worked with 4 students to build an interactive, multi-user game within 1 week. Consisting of 101 rooms, users can explore this retro cyberpunkinspired game and see other users in real-time.

- Learned Django in 1 day to deploy a RESTful API to Heroku and used PostgreSQL for data persistence.
- Implemented algorithm to generate spiral maze with which users can interact with and explore.
- Took on the role of UX/UI designer and created/implemented the retrocyberpunk aesthetic of the game using Figma.

Riders For Life | Oct 2019 - Nov 2019 | Demo Video

React, Redux, FrontlineSMS, Node, Express, GeoLib, PostgreSQL

Collaborated with a team consisting of 1 UX Designer and 6 Web Developers, as part of Lambda Labs, to create a two-part application for the non-profit 'Safe Mothers, Safe Babies' in Uganda.

- Worked with the non-profits' stake-holder for 8 weeks to increase the productivity, reliability, and usability of both parts of the application.
- Created an emergency SMS application allowing pregnant Ugandan mothers to request transportation to local health facilities from Boda drivers.
- Built an administrative dashboard that allows admin users to interact with mother/driver data collected on the ground in Uganda.

EXPERIENCE

Viking Enterprise Solutions | Front-End Developer | 2020 - Present Angular, HTML, Sass, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Material UI, Adobe XD

Designs, manufactures, and sells leading edge off-the-shelf and customized server and storage platforms for datacenters and enterprise markets.

- Responsible for designing the user experience for various cloud storage management software applications.
- Created wireframes and mockups through Adobe XD to establish design and brand principles to create consistency between all current and future software applications.
- Work within an Agile, Scrum, and collaborative team environment to develop the UI using Angular, Bootstrap, and Material frameworks and component libraries.

5150Whips | Web Developer & Designer | 2018 -2019

Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query

5150whips is an e-commerce site that offers remote-controlled multicolored LED lights for off-road vehicles such as UTV's, RZR's, quads, and more.

- Hired as a web developer to refactor, fix, maintain and make updates to the existing website at the time.
- Worked closely with the client to rebuild and redesign a new website that better-represented company brand, theme, and customers.

Freelance, Cryptocurrency | Graphic Designer | 2018 -2019

Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign

Art Deco-inspired presentational booklet cover, that explained cryptocurrency, mining cryptocurrncy, and how to build and operate a cryptocurrency mining rig.

- Used as part of the clients' presentation to convince immediate managers and department heads of the benefits of cryptocurrency investing.
- Collaborated with the client on creating a unique and engaging design that would catch the attention of his peers and managers.